在上一集里
Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
天下没有白吃的午餐
Few things of value come without a price.
你想要什么回报？
What is it that you wish in return?
小人只愿重回霸天虎之列
Only to be a Decepticon once again.
这次您想知道什么呢 我的君王？
Now, what will we be fishing for today, my liege?
红蜘蛛的真实意图！
Starscream's true motives.
啊 高贵强大的天震
Ah, the high-and-mighty Skyquake.
你应该听我号令！
You shall bow to my command.
融为一体 哈哈哈…我感觉到了！
Symbiosis. Hahaha... I can feel it!
完了…
Awkward.
我允许你重回我们的队伍
I will allow you to return to our ranks.
我的个娘啊…感谢火种源！
Oh! Thank the Allspark!
嘿 别看我没能当成首个踏上塞博特恩的人类
You know, I might not be the first human on Cybertron
可我还是能成为历史上第一个人类交换生！
but I can still be the first human exchange student.
干嘛不早点告诉我们“终极之钥”的事？
Why didn't you tell us about the Omega keys before?
或许你没注意到
You probably didn't notice
最近情势有些紧张
but things have been kind of intense around here lately.
这么说…你们真的能在短期内回家了？
So, you guys could really be going home soon, huh?
别担心 拉夫
Don't worry, Raf.
你随时能来看我们
You'll come visit!
等咱们安顿好住处之后 他也可以随时来访
Once we get our place set up, he can bunk with us.
对吧 小隔？
Right, Bulk?
呃…神子
Uh, Miko?
你会带我去的 对吧？
You are taking me with you, right?
咱们是不是高兴得早了点儿？
Aren't we getting ahead of ourselves here?
别说咱们现在无法到达塞博特恩
Not only do we lack any actual method of reaching Cybertron
就连唯一能复兴星球的工具都在红蜘蛛的手里
but Starscream now controls the sole means of our planet's restoration.
那是我们仅有的情报…
As far as we know.
您的意思是红蜘蛛可能又回虎窝了？
You think Starscream's rejoined the Cons?
他可能会用“终极之钥”去讨威震天的欢心
He might've used the Omega keys to buy back Megatron's favor.
哼…他就是个奸商 想看谁出价更高
Hmph. Without first trying to sell them to the highest bidder?
我敢说他不久就会联系我们 并且…
It wouldn't surprise me if he had the nerve to contact us and...
好吧 救大半仙！
Okay, that's weird.
真是红蜘蛛啊？
Is it Starscream?
不 是骇翼
No. It is Dreadwing.
他想和我们见一面
And he wants to meet.
放下武器！
Drop your weapons!
举起手来！
Hands where we can see them!
我不是来战斗的
I am not here to fight
而是来给你们送这个
but to give you this.
卓天越之锤？
The Forge of Solus Prime.
可能装着炸弹
Could be rigged to blow.
骇翼
Dreadwing
你想要什么回报？
what do you ask in return?
你能善加使用就是最好的报答
Only that you use it wisely.
那么“终极之钥”呢？
And? The Omega keys?
在威震天手里
In Megatron's possession
守卫森严
under heaviest guard.
小红真的和霸天虎勾结了！
Scream did make a deal with the Cons.
你用意何在？
Why?
霸天虎之名已被他们玷污了
A shadow of disgrace has been cast upon the Decepticons.
我不愿再与之为伍
It is a cause I no longer wish to be part of.
那么 我再次请求你
Then I appeal to you again.
加入我们 同心协力 让这场战争彻底终结！
Join us and help end this conflict once and for all.
背叛我的族群…
Betraying my kind
不代表就要加入你的队伍
is not the same as accepting yours.
这虽然不是星辰剑
It's no Star Saber
但我敢说它肯定能砸碎威震天的剑
but I bet it can shatter Megatron's blade
顺便砸扁他那张丑脸！
and put some dents into that ugly mug of his.
这锤子不是那么用的
It's not that kind of hammer.
既然四块“终极之钥”都在霸天虎手里
With the Decepticons in possession of all four Omega keys
那我们不妨用这锤子复制出新的！
a more appropriate use of the Forge would be to use it to replicate our own.
即便锤子有这种力量
Even with such power
我也没有足够的专业知识来进行这种高级复制
their reconstruction would require a level of expertise I do not possess.
那我们只能祈祷威震天不会毁掉所有钥匙
I guess we better hope Megatron doesn't destroy the keys
以防其他人可以回家
to prevent anyone from ever going home.
威震天虽然邪恶无比
Megatron may be evil
但我相信他会让这些钥匙物尽其用的
but I believe he will use the keys for their intended purpose.
那干嘛不让他拿去 也省了咱们的麻烦？
Then I say we let him keep them and do the work for us.
我是说 由谁来复苏塞博特恩有区别吗？
W... I mean, what difference does it make who restores Cybertron?
如果威震天让塞博特恩重生了
If Megatron revives Cybertron
他必定会借此来扩大自己的政治影响
he will no doubt use it to his political advantage.
这…我…听不懂了
Y-you lost me.
十有八九
In all likelihood
霸天虎的头目会将自己描绘为救世主
the leader of the Decepticons will portray himself as our planet's savior
将汽车人污蔑为战犯
and brand all Autobots as war criminals.
继续这场巨大的骗局…
The grand deception continues.
威震天的“功绩”可能会影响塞博特恩几百万年
Megatron's so-called "achievement" could influence Cybertron for eons to come
荼毒返回家园的塞博特恩人的火种和心灵
poisoning the sparks and minds of its returning citizens...
这可不是理想的新时代的开端
hardly the ideal way to begin a new age.
但我们仍有希望
But there is hope.
威震天虽然已得到了“终极之钥”
For while Megatron may have the keys
他依然没有发现“终极之锁”的存在
he has yet to discover the existence of the Omega lock itself.
“终极之锁？”
Omega lock?
等等…现在是我听不懂了
Wait... now you lost me.
那正是“终极之钥”用以激活的东西
That which the four relics were designed to activate.
我们必须抢在威震天前面找到它
We must locate the device before Megatron does
并严加保护 直到我们夺回钥匙
and secure it until we can recover the keys.
可已经没有未破解的铁堡信息了
There are no more Iacon entries to decode.
“终极之锁”可能在地球上的任何地方
This lock could be anywhere on Earth!
事实上…
Actually...
它在塞博特恩上
It is on Cybertron.
什么？！
What?
你是怎么知道的？
How do you know?
是钛师傅在星辰剑中所传递的信息里说的
Alpha Trion revealed its location to me during the message conveyed by the Star Saber.
你干嘛不早告诉我们？
And you didn't think to tell us.
是钛师傅嘱咐的
Alpha Trion did not wish it so.
有了“卓天越之锤”
With the Forge of Solus Prime
我们就有了回到塞博特恩的办法
we now possess the means of reaching Cybertron.
我必须加紧工作
I must work quickly
以便尽快利用我们在战略上所取得的优势
as our tactical advantage over Megatron will not last long.
骇翼
Dreadwing.
我一直在找你
I have been searching for you.
随时为您效劳 威震天陛下
I am at your service, Lord Megatron.
我明白红蜘蛛的归来令你有些…难堪
I recognize that Starscream's return to our ranks may be... difficult for you
毕竟你的兄弟是因他而死
given the loss of your twin under his command.
但你的配合是必要的
But your cooperation is essential.
霸天虎只有团结一致 才能复苏和领导塞博特恩
We Decepticons will be best-equipped to rule a restored Cybertron only if we are united.
属下明白
Understood.
假如您乐意的话 主人
And if it pleases you, master
属下愿意以私人身份去和我们的战友沟通
I intend to reach out to our comrade... personally.
该起床了
Rise and shine!
你的变形齿轮移植手术很成功
Your T-cog transplant was a success.
没错 哥就是这么给力！
Yes, I am just that good.
啊…终于！
Ah... finally.
我都等不及飞起来 在云间穿梭了
I can't wait to take flight and soar above the clouds.
红蜘蛛
Starscream.
很遗憾地通知你
I regret to inform you
你再也不会有机会展翅高飞了
that you will not live to spread your wings
再也不会！
ever again.
击倒 救我！
Knockout, help me!
骇翼 你到底怎么了？
Dreadwing, what has gotten into you?
哦！慢着！是天震的事儿吗？我还以为这事儿过去了！
Oh. Wait. This is about Skyquake, isn't it? I thought we had put that behind us!
是过去了！
So had I!
刀剑无眼 沙场伤亡乃兵家常事！
Casualties are an unfortunate consequence of war!
我保证令兄的牺牲是光荣的！
But I assure you, your twin met his end with great honor!
但你玷污了他的荣耀！糟践了他的尸体！
Which you disgraced by raising him from the dead!
呃…被你发现了…
Oh, you know about that.
我一定能为你做些什么！
There must be something I can do
我可以补偿你 减轻你的痛苦！
some form of reparation I can offer to alleviate your anguish!
用你的火种就够了！
Your spark will suffice!
骇翼！
Dreadwing!
退下！
Stand down!
这个玷污我兄长的人必须付出代价！
This desecrator must pay for his actions!
您管这叫忠心吗 主人？！
You call this loyalty, master?!
我让你退下！这是命令！
I said stand down! That is an order.
恕难从命！
One which I cannot follow.
啊…我没死！我没死！
I'm okay? I'm okay!
威震天陛下 小人将永感大恩大德！
Lord Megatron, you have my eternal thanks.
别让我后悔今天的选择
Do not ever make me regret which one of you I spared.
是我胡思乱想了
Is it my imagination
还是擎天柱最近有点不对头？
or has Optimus been acting differently
自从他接收了钛师傅的信息之后
since that message from Alpha Trion?
嗯…他是隐瞒了咱们一些事
Yeah, he has been keeping things from us.
连救护车他都瞒着
Even Ratchet's out of the loop.
给我一个理由
Well, give me one good reason
为什么擎天柱不能信任我们这些队友？
Optimus couldn't trust his own teammates
隐瞒了“终极之锁”的存在？
why he couldn't have told us about the Omega lock.
因为如果他说了的话
Because if he had
威震天就会从我的脑袋里得到这信息…用那读心设备
Megatron would've pulled it out of my head with his patch.
那有什么关系
Like it matters.
反正虎子们已经得到所有钥匙了…
The Cons are holding all the keys anyway.
时间不等人啊 击倒！
Tick tock, Knockout. Tick tock!
威震天正等待结果呢！
Megatron's expecting results
你也看到他现在心情很差
and given what we just witnessed
我说咱们可决不能让主人失望了！
I would say that we cannot afford to disappoint our master.
“咱们”？
We?
你连根手指都没动
Unless nagging counts
就会在一边絮叨！
I haven't seen you lift a finger!
我已经为他弄回来钥匙了
I am the one who brought him the keys.
我用不着再靠弄清钥匙的用法…
Do I really need to prove myself further
来证明自己的价值了吧？
by deciphering how they operate, too?
哼…要不是某人让我给他做了整形手术
Well, perhaps if my research hadn't been sidelined by someone's cosmetic surgery
我的研究没准儿已经大有进展了!
I might be further along right now!
哼…还是给我看看吧！
Oh, just give it here!
哦 天呐 我怎么没想到这招？
Oh, gee. Why didn't I think of that?
你也这么想的吗…？
Do you think...
准备好了？插！
Ready... go!
哈哈哈 这就是为什么骇翼只配拧螺钉
Hahaha. And that is why Dreadwing is pushing up lug nuts.
…而我们坐办公室
And we are not.
原来如此！
Of course!
如果没有“锁”的话 “钥匙”的存在就毫无意义了
Keys are useless without something to unlock.
将太空桥指向塞博特恩！
Target the space bridge for Cybertron.
又是一个惊人的魔幻般的科学奇迹
Yet another astonishing convergence of magic and science
感谢先祖遗赠
courtesy of the ancients.
还有咱们的头儿
And our leader.
难以置信 仅仅挥舞了几下锤子 砰的一下！
It's hard to believe... a few swings of that hammer, and bam!
环陆桥就变成太空桥了
Our ground bridge is now a space bridge.
探测器检测到地球大气层外有大规模能量爆发
Our sensors are detecting a massive Energon burst occurring outside Earth's atmosphere.
这种爆发只有一种可能…
A surge of that kind could only mean one thing...
另一座太空桥被启动了！
Activation of another space bridge.
威震天已经发现“终极之锁”在塞博特恩了
Megatron has discovered that the Omega lock is on Cybertron.
看起来咱们已经失去了优势
It appears we have lost our advantage.
但威震天并不知道我们也可以星际旅行了
But with Megatron unaware that we now possess the means of interstellar travel
只要出其不意 攻其不备 我们仍有机会
the element of surprise remains in our favor.
为了这次的任务 我们必须祭出所有看家法宝
We must embark on this mission with every resource at our disposal.
红蜘蛛 我不在的期间由你指挥
Starscream. Assume command in my absence.
荣幸之至 主人！
I would be honored, master.
他又在打造什么呢？
What's he forging now?
必须阻止威震天 不惜一切代价！\N（86大电影台词）
Megatron must be stopped, no matter the cost.
根据钥匙显示的标志物
According to the landmarks displayed by the keys
我们寻找的目标就深埋于“锈海”之中
the object we seek is located deep the within the Sea of Rust.
（Sea of Rust 锈海 位于塞博特恩赤道 由不稳定的行星物质和粒子流组成的区域 时常释放出具有腐蚀性 但相对无害的气体）
擎天柱？
Ah! Optimus?
不 救护车 是我 杰克
Uh, n-no, Ratchet. It's Jack.
有什么事发生了吗？
Is something wrong?
放学都快一个小时了
'Cause school's been out for almost an hour, and
还没人来接我们
no one's showed to pick us up.
那是因为这会儿整个小队都…有事在身
That is because the entire team is rather... indisposed at the moment.
我建议你们今天换种方式回家吧
I suggest you obtain an alternate method of transport.
他说什么？
What's he saying?
嗯…轮子们忙着呢
Eh... The bots are busy.
那就让救护车来接咱们嘛
Then tell Ratchet to come get us!
他可是个大~闲~人~
It's not like he has anything else to do!
总之你们先回家
Just go home!
我稍后再联系你们
I will be in touch later!
喂？喂？
He... hello?
他挂掉了
He hung up.
他又在搞什么飞机？
What crawled up his tailpipe and died?
他有告诉你出什么事了吗？
Did Ratchet tell you what's going on?
没有 他们最近好像一直神秘兮兮的
No. They seem to be keeping us in the dark a lot lately.
怎么？发生什么事了？
Wha... what just happened?
烟幕？
Smokescreen?
这怎么可能！
But that's impossible.
汽车人应该没法到达…
The Autobots do not possess the means to...
干掉他们！
Crush them!
保护好钥匙！
Defend the keys!
我已经击碎过一次你的剑了
I bested your little blade once
大不了再来一次！
and I shall do it again!
如果拿不回钥匙
I will have those keys
我就收了你们的火种！
or I will have your sparks!
后面那件事我可以代劳！
I can help with the last part.
火种剥离器！
The spark extractor!
红蜘蛛！
Starscream!
汽车人已经抢走了“终极之钥”
The Autobots have seized the Omega keys.
立刻派援军过来！
Send reinforcements immediately!
这个嘛 威震天陛下
Actually, lord Megatron
声波和我说了近期的一些情况
Soundwave has been briefing me on recent developments
我们或许已经有了更有效的解决办法
and we may have a more effective solution.
咱们不会领先太久的
Our head start won't last long.
这就是钛师傅说的地点 对吗？
This is where Alpha Trion said we'd find it, right?
坐标是没错
These are the coordinates.
看起来不像啊
Doesn't look like much.
救护车 我们已经找到“终极之锁”了
Ratchet, we have located the Omega lock.
终于…
At last.
根据钛师傅所言
According to Alpha Trion
“终极之锁”就是直接联通火种源的渠道
the Omega lock is a conduit to the very Allspark itself.
擎天柱 如此重大的荣誉
Optimus, an honor like this
不应该属于我
shouldn't belong to me.
汽车人
Autobots
我建议你们停下手头的工作
I would suggest that you put a halt to your task...
把钥匙交给我
and hand over those keys.
凭什么？
And why would we do that?
就凭这些人类都在我手里
So that I may hand over the humans.
如果我们拒绝呢？
And if we refuse?
那我别无选择 只好打开那些舱体
Then I will have no choice but to open the pods
让你们的宠物暴露在塞博特恩剧毒的空气之中
exposing your pets to Cybertron's toxic atmosphere.
然后
And then
我们就可以看着他们一起…痛苦地死去！
we can all watch them instantly perish, together.